## Felipe Paes de Oliveira

fpo@felipeweb.dev / +55 11 99930-9974 www.linkedin.com/in/felipewebcloud

Proactive, responsible Java and Go developer focused on distributed systems. Known to possess strong technical knowledge and to deliver solid systems. More than 5 years of experience developing successful systems in Brazil that have increased revenue. Active in open source communities such as GitHub.

### **KEY COMPETENCIES**

Software engineering Distributed systems Open source

Programming Project Management Microservices

Back-end Rest API Artificial intelligence

### **EDUCATION**

- College Paulista of Informatics and Management (FIAP), Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil
  - Bachelor Degree in Information Systems
- College Paulista of Informatics and Management (FIAP), Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil
  - Postgraduate Degree in Cloud Computing

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Nuveo Smart Cloud / Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil / July 2018 - Now Technical Team Lead

Nuveo is a Brazilian company that use computer vision to extract data from images or files and automate some manual processes

- To help my team to make the technical decision most of the time as a judgment
- To help junior developers in my team as a mentor
- Facilitator of my team's scrum meetings
- To go to technical meetings with our clients
- To help our open source projects community as a project lead

## Nuveo Smart Cloud / Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil / November 2016 - July 2018 Senior Software Engineer

Nuveo is a Brazilian company that use computer vision to extract data from images or files and automate some manual processes

 To develop some REST, JSON RPC API and GRPC API for Nuveo Core Application

# Caelum / Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil / August 2014 - August 2016 Java Developer / Instructor

Caelum is a brazilian extracurricular programming school.

- To develop a custom ERP system that helps the business management
- To teach classes about JPA and Webservices in Java

# Alura / Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil / January 2016 - August 2016 Java Developer / Instructor

Alura is a Brazilian e-learning platform like Udacity.

- To add new features at Alura using Java
- To create a course about MongoDB

## Soul Web Design / Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil / July 2013 - January 2016 Java Developer / PHP Developer / Go Developer

Soul Web Design was a Brazilian software house.

To develop software that solves our client's difficulties using Go, Java or PHP

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Portuguese Native
- English Advanced

#### **COURSES AND CERTIFICATES**

- Mongo DB; Alura: 2016
- Oratory; Reinaldo Polito Institute: 2015
- Web Services and advanced Java EE; Caelum: 2014

## **ADDITIONAL CREDENTIALS**

TECHNICAL SKILLS	Go / AWS / Trello / Git / Scrum / PostgreSQL / Oracle PL/SQL / Nomad / Consul / Vault
OTHER ACTIVITIES AND PROJECTS	<ul> <li>Author of Osin MySQL lib         (https://github.com/felipeweb/osin-mysql)</li> <li>Author of HTML Render lib         (https://github.com/felipeweb/htmlrender)</li> <li>Core Team of Gofn         (https://github.com/gofn/gofn)</li> <li>Contributor of Tsuru         (https://github.com/tsuru/tsuru)</li> <li>Contributor of Go Cloud         (https://www.go-macaron.com)</li> <li>Core Team of pREST (http://postgres.rest)</li> <li>Contributor of Docker (https://www.docker.com)</li> <li>Blogging at https://felipeweb.dev</li> </ul>